[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "round": "round3",
    "subject": "Science",
    "question": "Deficiency of Vitamin A can lead to which disease?",
    "ans": [
      "Beri Beri",
      "Rickets",
      "Night Blindness",
      "Goiter disease"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "विटामिन ए की कमी से कौन सा रोग हो सकता है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "बेरी बेरी",
      "सुखा रोग",
      "रतौंधी",
      "घेंघा"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Night Blindness",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "subject": "Science",
    "round": "round3",
    "question": "Measles is caused by which Pathogen?",
    "ans": [
      "Algae",
      "Bacteria",
      "Virus",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "खसरा किस रोगाणु द्वारा होती है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "शैवाल",
      "जीवाणु",
      "विषाणु",
      "इनमे से कोई नहीं"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Virus",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "subject": "Science",
    "round": "round3",
    "question": "Which disease can be prevented by Vaccination?",
    "ans": [
      "Polio",
      "Dengue",
      "Dysentery",
      "Typhoid"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "कौन सी बिमारी टीकाकरण द्वारा रोका जा सकता है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "पोलियो",
      "डेंगू",
      "पेचिश",
      "टाइफाइड"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Polio",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "subject": "Science",
    "round": "round3",
    "question": "What type of disease is Tuberculosis (T.B)?",
    "ans": [
      "Contagious",
      "Non - Infectious",
      "Genetic",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "तपेदिक टी बी किस प्रकार का रोग है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "संक्रामक",
      "असंक्रामक",
      "अनुवांशिक",
      "इनमे से कोई नहीं"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Contagious",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "subject": "Science",
    "round": "round3",
    "question": "Which cell organelle is not found in plant cell?",
    "ans": [
      "Nucleus",
      "Centrosome",
      "Golgi Body",
      "Cell Membrane"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "कौन सी कोशिकांग पादप कोशिका में नहीं पायी जाती है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "केन्द्रक",
      "सेंट्रोसोम",
      "गॉल्जीकाय",
      "कोशिका झिल्ली"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Centrosome",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "subject": "Science",
    "round": "round3",
    "question": "Which is the Longest Cell in the Human Body?",
    "ans": [
      "Blood Cells",
      "Nerve Cells",
      "Fat Cells",
      "Bone Cells"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "मानव शरीर में सबसे लंबी कोशिका कौन सी है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "रक्त कोशिकाएं",
      "तंत्रिका कोशिकाएं",
      "वसा कोशिकाएं",
      "अस्थि कोशिकाएं"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Nerve Cells",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "subject": "Science",
    "round": "round3",
    "question": "Organism that carries Pathogens from the Patient to the new Host?",
    "ans": [
      "Amoeba",
      "Bacteria",
      "Vector",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "रोगाणुओं को रोगी से लेकर अन्य नए पोषी तक पहुंचने वाले जंतु को क्या कहते हैं?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "अमीबा",
      "जीवाणु",
      "रोगवाहक",
      "इनमे से कोई नहीं"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Vector",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "subject": "Science",
    "round": "round3",
    "question": "Cells that have a Membranous organized Nucleus are called?",
    "ans": [
      "Cell Membrane",
      "Prokaryotic Cell",
      "Eukaryotic Cell",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "जिन कोशिकाओं में झिल्लियुक्त संगठित केन्द्रक पाया जाता है क्या कहलाता है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "कोशिका झिल्ली",
      "प्रोकार्योटिक कोशिका",
      "यूकेरियोटिक कोशिका",
      "इनमे से कोई नहीं"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Eukaryotic Cell",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "subject": "Science",
    "round": "round3",
    "question": "Size of the smallest Animal Cell is?",
    "ans": [
      "1 – 10 meters",
      "1 – 10 centimeters",
      "1 -10 millimeters",
      "0.1 – 0.5 micrometers"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "सबसे छोटी जीवाणु कोशिका का साइज?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "1 – 10 मीटर",
      "1 – 10 सेंटीमीटर",
      "1 -10 मी मीटर",
      "0.1 – 0.5 माइक्रोमीटर"
    ],
    "correctAns": "0.1 – 0.5 micrometers",
    "enable": true
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "subject": "Science",
    "round": "round3",
    "question": "Smoking, Chewing Tobacco and Consumption of Alcohol can generate which disease?",
    "ans": [
      "Common Cold",
      "Cholera",
      "Fatal disease",
      "Dysentery"
    ],
    "questionHindi": "घूम्रपान, तंबाकू चबाना तथा शराब का सेवन करने से कौन सा रोग उत्पन्न हो सकता है?",
    "ansHindi": [
      "सामान्य जुकाम",
      "हैज़ा",
      "घातक रोग",
      "पेचिश"
    ],
    "correctAns": "Fatal disease",
    "enable": true
  }
]